CHRISTOPHER M. DAVIES

NEW YORK, NY | MOBILE: 203.550.6743 | EMAIL: C.M.DAVIES10@GMAIL.COM

GITHUB: GITHUB.COM/CMDAVIES10 | PORTFOLIO: CMDAVIES10.GITHUB.IO/PORTFOLIO | LINKEDIN: LINKEDIN: COM/IN/DAVIESCM

SUMMARY

Full-Stack developer and software engineer with over ten years of experience in finance and corporate development across multiple industries. Firm believer that hard work, creativity and collaboration are crucial in achieving success. Excited to combine my extensive technical background in finance with programming to tackle greater and more complex challenges.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages, Databases & Libraries: JavaScript, CSS3, HTML5, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, React.js, Git, handlebars.js, Firebase, jQuery, Bootstrap, Bulma, Materialize, NPM (Axios, passport, D3, mongoose, sequelize, etc.), Visual Basic for Applications (VBA), Python, as well as, experience in Java

Software & Applications: GitHub, GitLab, Heroku, Asana, Figma, Slack, Excel, PowerPoint, Lightroom, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Bloomberg, CapIQ, ACT, Debt Wire, Thomson Reuters, Pitchbook, LCD Comps, Jitterbit, Stata, Dynamics

EXPERIENCE

MML Capital Partners | Consultant, Private Equity

Stamford, CT | Jun. 2018 - Aug. 2019

- Assisted in evaluating potential investment opportunities across the industrial services sector, including a proposed refinancing of a leading equipment service provider, given specific prior industry experience and knowledge.

Lampert Debt Advisors | Senior Associate, Leveraged Finance

New York, NY | Mar. 2015 – Oct. 2017

- Closed six deals totaling \$350 million while managing three junior analysts and an associate throughout entire deal lifecycles through in-depth operational and financial diligence, offering material preparation and credit agreement negotiations.
- Spearheaded the build-out of a proprietary digital marketplace for middle-market debt products and led digital initiative which included logo, website, and marketing material design.

TNT Crane & Rigging, Inc. | Associate, M&A and Corporate Finance

Houston, TX | Dec. 2012 - Feb. 2015

- Managed and supervised 22 branches across the U.S. with direct reporting to CEO, CFO and COO.
- Successfully acquired two large industry competitors Stampede & Eagle West (Canada) and Rent-a-Crane (Oklahoma).
- Provided critical diligence, analysis, and research to J.P. Morgan during the successful sale process of TNT to large P.E. firm.

SELECT PROJECTS

LIRI Bot | GitHub: github.com/cmdavies10/liri-node-app

- LIRI (Language Interpretation and Recognition Interface) is a command line node app that takes in parameters and gives back data. The app takes in user input and returns detailed information on upcoming concerts, songs and movies.
- Languages: NodeJS, JavaScript; NPM Packages: Axios, Moment and FS; APIs: Spotify, OMDB, and Bands in Town

NYT News Scraper | Deployed: quarded-tundra-18857.herokuapp.com | GitHub: qithub.com/cmdavies10/news-scraper

- New York Times News Scraper is a full-stack application that scrapes headlines and summaries from the NYT World Edition and allows users to view and post comments on each article.
- Languages: JavaScript, NodeJS, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars, Bootstrap; NPM Packages: Mongoose and Axios

GIF Finder | Deployed: cmdavies10.github.io/Gif-Finder | GitHub: github.com/cmdavies10/Gif-Finder

- GIF Finder is a web-based application that allows users to access and retrieve data from GIPHY API's extensive library, returning relevant GIFs based on search results. Search results provide the user with the option to toggle between static and animated states.
- Languages: JavaScript, CSS, HTML5, Bootstrap, ¡Query and AJAX

EDUCATION

Columbia University – School of Engineering & Applied Science | Coding Bootcamp Certificate

New York, NY | 2019

Washington & Lee University – Williams School of Commerce | B.A., Economics

Lexington, VA | Class of 2010

London School of Economics & Political Science | International Policy Analysis

London, U.K. | 2008